>> Are you ready, kids?
>> 孩子们，准备好了吗？
All: Aye, aye, Captain!
全体：是啊是啊，队长！
>> I can't hear you.
>> 我听不到你说话。
All: Aye, aye, Captain!
全体：是啊是啊，队长！
>> ♪ Ohh... ♪
>> ♪ 哦... ♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
All: SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
>> ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
>> ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
All: SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
>> ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
>> ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
All: SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：海绵宝宝！
>> ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
>> ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
All: SpongeBob SquarePants!
>> Ready?
全部：海绵宝宝！
>> 准备好了吗？
All: SpongeBob square pants!
全部：海绵宝宝方裤！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
海绵宝宝！
>> SpongeBob
>> 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
♪ ♪
>> 451, 452,
>> 451, 452,
453, 454,
455,
455、
456--Ow!
第456章 哎哟！
Nyah!
呀！
oh!
哦！
I split me nail.
我把指甲裂开了。
Oh, that looks terrible.
哦，那看起来很糟糕。
Hello?
Gwenevere?
你好？
格温薇尔？
It's an emergency.
是紧急状况。
No, I haven't been biting them.
不，我没有咬过它们。
Oh!
哦！
Can you just schedule me in?
你能安排我去吗？
Now?
现在？
A manicure
in the middle of the day?
一次美甲
在中午？
Yes, I want my nails
to look their best.
是的，我想要我的指甲
展现最好的自己。
I'll be right there.
我马上就到。
♪ ♪
>>
>>
>> Ow!
>> Ahoy, sir.
>> 噢！
>> 嘿，先生。
Where are you going?
>>
你要去哪里？
>>
It's--It's a secret.
这是——这是一个秘密。
>>
You have a secret?
>>
你有秘密吗？
>> Everybody's got a secret,
SpongeBob.
>> 每个人都有一个秘密，
海绵宝宝。
And mine's gonna take
15 minutes.
我的会采取
15分钟。
Maybe 20 if she can spruce up
me cuticles.
如果她能打扮得漂漂亮亮的话，也许20岁
我角质层。
>> Aye, aye, sir.
>> 是的，是的，先生。
And who will be  in charge
while you're gone?
谁将负责
当你离开的时候？
>> Eh...
>> 呃...
>>
>> Well, not Squidward.
>>
>> 好吧，不是章鱼哥。
Don't know him.
Too lumpy.
不认识他。
太块了。
Okay, okay.
好吧，好吧。
You're in charge.
你负责。
>> What?
>> You're in charge
>> 什么？
>> 你负责
for the next 15 minutes.
接下来的 15 分钟。
>> I'm....in....charge?
>> 我……负责……？
>> Yeah, sure.
Why not?
>> 是的，当然。
为什么不呢？
>> You okay, boy?
>> 你还好吗，孩子？
>>
>>
Yahoo!
雅虎！
I won't let you down, sir.
我不会让你失望的，先生。
>> Oh, sheesh.
>> 哦，天哪。
I'll be back in 15 minutes.
我 15 分钟后回来。
>>
>>
>> Ahem.
>> 咳咳。
Nap time's over, Squidward.
午睡时间结束了，章鱼哥。
Now what do you say
we work real hard
现在你说什么
我们工作非常努力
until Mr. Krabs comes back?
直到蟹老板回来？
>> Krabs is gone?
>> 螃蟹不见了？
>> Yep.
And I'm in charge
>> 是的。
我负责
for the next 15 minutes.
接下来的 15 分钟。
>> Wow.
>>
>> 哇。
>>
Yeah, I'm kind of a big deal
around here.
是的，我是个大人物
在这附近。
I guess that's why Krabs
put me in  charge.
我想这就是蟹蟹的原因
让我负责。
Charge.
收费。
♪ Charge ♪
♪ 充电 ♪
>> Wake me up when I care.
>> 当我关心时叫醒我。
>> No.
>> 没有。
Everything's under control,
people.
一切都在掌控之中
人们。
Go back to your Krabby Patties.
回去吃你的蟹肉饼吧。
Nothing your temporary
man in charge can't handle.
没有什么是你临时的
负责人无法处理。
Squidward?
>>
章鱼哥？
>>
>> Squidward?
>>
>> 章鱼哥？
>>
>> Squidward? Squidward?
>> 章鱼哥？章鱼哥？
Squid--Squid--Squidward?
鱿鱼——鱿鱼——章鱼哥？
Squid--Squid--
>> What?
鱿鱼--鱿鱼--
>> 什么？
>> Well, it's just
that I'm in...charge.
>> 嗯，只是
我负责。
>>
>>
And you interrupted
而你打断了
my regularly scheduled
Krusty Krab nap?
我定期安排的
蟹堡王小睡了吗？
>> Regularly scheduled nap?
>> 定期午睡？
>> This must be important.
>> 这一定很重要。
Mr. Krabs has never interrupted
one of these before.
蟹老板从来没有打断过
之前的其中之一。
>> Really?
>> 真的吗？
>> But being as you're
the "man in charge,"
>> 但做你自己
“负责人”
you must have your reasons.
你一定有你的理由。
>> Well, I--Um...
>> 嗯，我——嗯……
>> What is it?
>> 这是什么？
>> Uh, nothing.
>> 呃，没什么。
Carry on.
继续。
Boy, there sure is
a lot of procedural type stuff
男孩，肯定有
很多程序类型的东西
I don't know
about the Krusty Krab.
我不知道
关于蟹堡王。
>> Ha!
>> 哈！
Ding! Ding!
叮！叮！
>> Order up, Squidward!
>> 订购吧，章鱼哥！
>> You know, I'll let you
serve this one.
>> 你知道，我会让你
服务这个。
My stories are on.
我的故事正在上演。
>> Gosh, I'd love to, Squidward,
>> 天哪，我很乐意，章鱼哥，
but I've got to cook
the patties.
但我得做饭
肉饼。
>> So do it when you're done.
>> 所以当你完成后就去做吧。
>> And unclog the sink.
>> 并疏通水槽。
>> Hmm.
>> 嗯。
Would you like to hear
a secret?
你想听吗
一个秘密？
>> What kind of secret?
>> See that guy over there?
>> 什么样的秘密？
>> 看到那边那个人了吗？
>> Yes.
>> 是的。
>> He wants to be a fry cook,
and you're his hero.
>> 他想成为一名炒菜厨师，
而你是他的英雄。
>> Who, me?
>> 谁，我？
>> Why don't you give him
a couple of pointers?
>> 你为什么不给他
一些指示？
Let him cook his own patty.
让他自己煮肉饼。
And don't take no for an answer.
并且不要接受“不”的答案。
He's shy.
他很害羞。
>> Hey, buddy.
>> 嘿，伙计。
Yeah, it's me, SpongeBob.
是的，是我，海绵宝宝。
Fry cook  extraordinaire.
炒菜厨师非凡。
>> Uh, hello.
>> 呃，你好。
>> I know your secret.
>> 我知道你的秘密。
>> What?
Who told you?
>> 什么？
谁告诉你的？
>> Oh, a little cashier told me.
>>哦，一个小收银员告诉我的。
Follow me.
>> Yeah, whatever you say, man.
跟我来。
>> 是的，无论你说什么，伙计。
>> Moron.
>>白痴。
>> Bet you didn't think you'd be
in here today, did you?
>> 打赌你没想到你会是
今天在这里，你吗？
>> No.
>> First off, this is my grill.
>> 没有。
>> 首先，这是我的烤架。
This is where the magic happens.
这就是奇迹发生的地方。
And this is my actual spatula.
这是我真正的抹刀。
So, start frying up
some patties.
那么，开始炒吧
一些肉饼。
I'll check on you later,
my little prodigy.
稍后我会查看你的情况
我的小神童。
>> Ha-ha, SpongeBob
will believe anything.
>> 哈哈，海绵宝宝
会相信任何事情。
>> Order number 12!
>> SpongeBob!
>> 订单号12！
>> 海绵宝宝！
What are you doing?
你在干什么？
>> Taking out an order.
>> 取出订单。
>> You're serving Krabby Patties
>> 您正在供应蟹黄肉饼
with your hands?
用你的双手？
Do you know how filthy
your hands are?
你知道有多脏吗
你的手是？
>>
They are?
>>
他们是？
>> But your feet, however,
>> 但是你的脚，然而，
are nice and clean.
很干净。
Think about it.
想一想。
They've been protected
by your shoes and socks all day.
他们已被保护
一整天都在你的鞋子和袜子旁边。
>> Ohhhhh.
>> 噢噢噢。
It's all clear to me now.
现在我都清楚了。
One Krabby meal served with
extra-sanitary foot service.
一份蟹肉餐搭配
额外卫生的足部服务。
Your hot, steamy,
juicy Krabby patty,
你的热气腾腾，
多汁的蟹肉饼，
and a large drink.
和一大杯饮料。
♪ ♪
Enjoy.
享受。
>> Hey, is my food here yet?
>> 嘿，我的食物到了吗？
>> Here, you can have mine.
>> 在这里，你可以拥有我的。
>>
>>
>> Delivery.
>> What? What?
>> 交货。
>> 什么？什么？
>> Here's the supplies
you ordered.
>> 这是物资
你订购了。
>> Ow!
>> 噢！
>> Sign here.
>> 在此签名。
Hey, my pen.
嘿，我的笔。
>> Oops, sorry.
>> 哎呀，抱歉。
>> Hoo-huh!
>> 呼呼！
It's here!
就在这里！
♪ It's here! It's here! ♪
♪ 来了！就在这里！ ♪
♪ It's here! ♪
♪ 来了！ ♪
♪ Doo doo doo
doo doo doo doo ♪
♪ 嘟嘟嘟
嘟嘟嘟嘟♪
♪ It's here! ♪
♪ 来了！ ♪
>> SpongeBob,
what is all this junk?
>> 海绵宝宝,
这些垃圾是什么？
>> Now that I'm "in charge,"
>> 现在我“负责”了
I've decided to redecorate
the Krusty Krab.
我决定重新装修
蟹堡王。
I'm going to make it all pretty.
我会让这一切变得美好。
>> Yeah, have fun with that.
>> 是的，玩得开心。
>> ♪ Oh, Squidward. ♪
>> ♪ 哦，章鱼哥。 ♪
I'm in charge.
>> Oof!
我负责。
>> 噢！
>> So you'll be having
all the fun.
>> 所以你将会拥有
所有的乐趣。
>> Doing what?
>> 做什么？
Painting the walls,
粉刷墙壁，
buffing the tables,
sewing pretty curtains,
擦亮桌子，
缝制漂亮的窗帘，
washing the windows,
varnishing the stools,
清洗窗户，
给凳子涂清漆，
hanging the ferns,
waxing the toilets.
悬挂蕨类植物，
给厕所打蜡。
Oh, you lucky dog!
>>
哦，你这幸运的狗！
>>
Hey, SpongeBob,
嘿，海绵宝宝，
do you wanna hear
another Krusty Krab secret?
你想听吗
蟹堡王的另一个秘密？
>> Huh?
Another Krusty Krab secret?
>> 嗯？
蟹堡王的另一个秘密？
>> Yep.
Do you want to know
>> 是的。
你想知道吗
how Mr. Krabs gets
all these customers?
蟹老板是怎么得到的
所有这些客户？
>> Yesssss.
>> 是的。
>> Low expectations.
>> 低期望。
>> What's that?
>> 那是什么？
>> He keeps the place a dump
>> 他把这个地方变成了垃圾场
so the food seems even better
by comparison.
所以食物看起来更好
通过比较。
So if you want to impress
Mr. Krabs,
所以如果你想给人留下深刻印象
蟹老板先生，
you make it more filthy.
你让它变得更肮脏。
>> More filthy?
>> 更脏？
>> Throw trash on the floors,
break furniture,
>> 将垃圾扔在地板上，
打破家具，
and never clean anything.
并且从不清洁任何东西。
>> Sounds like the Chum Bucket.
>> 听起来像“密友桶”。
>> Ahhh, but you'll be doing it
on purpose.
>> 啊哈，但你会这么做的
故意的。
>> Ohhhh.
>> 哦哦。
>> How's this, Squidward?
>> 怎么样，章鱼哥？
>> Looking good.
>> 看起来不错。
>> You mean, looking bad.
>> 你的意思是，看起来很糟糕。
Enjoy our fine decor.
享受我们精美的装饰。
>> Next time, I'm picking
the restaurant.
>> 下次我选
餐厅。
♪ ♪
>> One Krusty Krab
covered in mud and slime.
>> 蟹堡王一只
被泥土和粘液覆盖。
>>
You missed a spot.
>>
你错过了一个地方。
♪ ♪
>> Oh.
>>哦。
Got it!
知道了！
♪ ♪
Bang!
砰!
Bang, bang, bang!
砰，砰，砰！
Gum under all tables.
所有桌子下都有口香糖。
How's that for low expectations?
期望值低怎么办？
>> Lower.
>> 降低。
>> Initiating Stage Two:
>> 启动第二阶段：
collateral damage.
附带损害。
How was that?
怎么样？
>> Perfect!
>> 完美！
>> Hey.
>> 嘿。
>> This place is disgusting.
>> Yeah, let's get out of here,
>> 这个地方太恶心了。
>> 是的，我们离开这里吧，
just as soon as I finish
this delicious Krabby patty.
我一完成
这个美味的蟹肉饼。
>> Squidward,
all the customers are leaving!
>> 章鱼哥,
所有的顾客都走了！
>> What did we talk about?
>> 我们聊了什么？
>> Don't touch the material--
>> 请勿触摸材质--
>> If you want
the customers to stay,
>> 如果你愿意
顾客留下来，
you need to provide
some entertainment.
你需要提供
一些娱乐。
>> Ooh, can do, Squidward!
Can do!
>> 噢，可以，章鱼哥！
可以做！
>> Come on, let's go.
>> 来吧，我们走吧。
>> Wait!
>> 等等！
>> What's he doing?
>> 他在做什么？
>> He's dancing.
>> 他在跳舞。
>>
>>
>> Okay, people,
just back away slowly.
>> 好的，各位，
慢慢后退。
>>
>>
there's nothing
like polished pincers
没有什么
像抛光的钳子
to make you feel like a man.
让你感觉自己像个男人。
Let's see how SpongeBob's doing
as acting manager.
让我们看看海绵宝宝是怎么做的
作为代理经理。
What the--
什么是——
SpongeBob dancing
like a goofball?
海绵宝宝跳舞
像个傻瓜？
>> ♪ And a hey and a ho ♪
>> ♪ 嘿嘿 ♪
♪ And a hey and a ho ♪
♪ 嘿嘿 ♪
♪ And a hey ho ha ho
hey ho ha ho ♪
♪ 嘿嘿嘿嘿
嘿嘿嘿嘿♪
>> Me customers
cowering in fear?
>> 我的客户
因恐惧而畏缩？
>> Help us.
>> 帮助我们。
>>
>>
The Krusty Krab a filthy mess!
蟹堡王真是一团糟！
>> Order number 20
ready for pick up.
>> 订单号 20
准备好接机。
>> And some stranger
cooking Krabby Patties!
>>还有一些陌生人
烹饪蟹肉饼！
Squidward sleeping on the job!
章鱼哥在工作中睡觉！
Okay, that's actually normal.
好吧，这其实很正常。
SpongeBob!
海绵宝宝！
What have you done
to me Krusty Krab?
你做了什么
对我来说蟹堡王？
>> I was just following
Squidward's advice, Mr. Krabs.
>> 我只是在关注
章鱼哥的建议，蟹老板。
He told me all your secrets.
他告诉了我你所有的秘密。
>> All me secrets?
>> 都是我的秘密？
So is there anything else
I can do for you,
那么还有什么其他的吗
我能为你做的，
acting manager SpongeBob?
代理经理海绵宝宝？
Ah!
啊!
Ah, Gwenevere!
啊，格温薇尔！
♪ ♪
>>
>>
Aaahh!
啊啊啊！
Hello?
你好？
>> Hey, SpongeBob.
How's it going?
>> 嘿，海绵宝宝。
怎么样了？
>> Oh, hiya, Sandy.
>> 哦，嗨，桑迪。
>> Hey, listen.
>> 嘿，听着。
I was wondering
if you could come by tonight.
我想知道
如果你今晚能过来的话。
Sure.
What's up?
当然。
这是怎么回事？
I whipped up a new invention
我想出了一项新发明
that I'm gonna unveil tonight
in front of my comrades,
今晚我要揭晓
在我的战友面前，
and I need  you  to be
my test subject.
我需要你
我的测试对象。
>> I will be there.
>> 我会在那里。
>> You're not gonna forget,
are you?
>> 你不会忘记，
你是吗？
>> Of course not.
Have I ever let you down before?
>> 当然不是。
我以前有让你失望过吗？
Plop!
扑通！
Hello?
你好？
>> Just be here!
>> 就在这里！
>> With Gary as my witness,
>> 有加里为我见证，
I will not let you down,
Miss Cheeks!
我不会让你失望的，
脸颊小姐！
I won't let Sandy down.
我不会让桑迪失望的。
>> How the barnacles do you put
this thing together?
>> 藤壶怎么放
这东西在一起？
>> I won't let Sandy down.
>> 我不会让桑迪失望。
I won't let Sandy down.
Mornin', capt'n.
我不会让桑迪失望的。
早上好，船长。
I won't let Sandy down.
我不会让桑迪失望的。
I won't let Sandy down, down.
I won't let Sandy down.
我不会让桑迪失望的。
Right after work, I'm going
straight over to Sandy's,
下班后我马上就去
直接去桑迪家，
who I'm not gonna let down.
>> Boy!
我不会让谁失望。
>> 男孩！
>> Yes, sir.
>> 是的，先生。
>> I've got a special assignment
for you.
>> 我有一项特殊任务
为了你。
This is a build-it-yourself
telescope.
这是自己搭建的
望远镜。
Only problem is,
唯一的问题是，
I can't figure out how to put
the darn thing together.
我不知道如何放置
该死的事情在一起。
That's where you come in.
这就是你进来的地方。
>> "Telescope Assembly Manual."
>>《望远镜组装手册》。
>> Now read this cover to cover
>> 现在请阅读本封面
and be prepared to put
this thing together at me house
并准备好投入
我家的这件事
tonight.
>> Tonight?
今晚。
>> 今晚？
>> That's not gonna be
a problem, is it?
>> 那不会是这样
有问题，是吗？
>> Um, well, actually--
>> 嗯，好吧，实际上——
>> Excellent!
>> 太棒了！
Because I was looking
因为我在寻找
at your annual employee
report card,
在您的年度员工处
报告卡、
and it appears
看来
the "does a laborious task
for supervisor" box
“做一项艰巨的任务
对于主管”框
has not been checked.
尚未检查。
>>
>>
>> See you tonight.
>> 今晚见。
>> What am I gonna do?
>> 我要做什么？
You can do it.
你可以做到的。
You made the commitments.
You'll have to honor them--
你做出了承诺。
你必须向他们致敬——
Both of them.
>> Who you talking to, buddy?
他们两个。
>> 伙计，你在和谁说话？
>> Ah!
>> 啊！
Oh, hiya, Patrick.
哦，嗨，帕特里克。
What are you doing back here?
你回来做什么？
>> Uh, sorry to disturb you
during work hours,
>> 呃，抱歉打扰您
在工作时间，
but I just wanted to remind you
about my birthday.
但我只是想提醒你
关于我的生日。
>> No need to remind me.
>> 不用提醒我。
I wouldn't forget
my best buddy's birthday.
我不会忘记
我最好的朋友的生日。
>> Then why aren't you saying
the words?
>>那你为什么不说
的话？
>> What words?
>> 什么话？
>> "Happy birthday."
>>“生日快乐。”
It's today!
My birthday is today!
就在今天！
今天是我的生日！
And you surely must remember
而你一定一定记得
what you're supposed to bring
to my birthday, right?
你应该带什么
到我生日了，对吗？
>> Uh--
>> My birthday cake!
>> 呃--
>> 我的生日蛋糕！
You're supposed to bring
my birthday cake!
你应该带
我的生日蛋糕！
>> Tonight?
>> Yes, tonight!
>> 今晚？
>> 是的，今晚！
Oh, when else am I gonna
celebrate it?
哦，我还要什么时候
庆祝吗？
At least I had the courtesy
to start my party
至少我有礼貌
开始我的聚会
after my best friend
got off work.
在我最好的朋友之后
下班了。
See you tonight...
今晚见...
Buddy.
伙伴。
>> Oh, Neptune.
>>哦，海王星。
This is worse
than I ever could've imagined.
这更糟糕
超出我的想象。
Right.
正确的。
Time to be all I can be.
是时候尽我所能了。
Man, these people
sure look sciencey.
伙计，这些人
当然看起来很科学。
Sandy must be pulling out
all the stops for this one.
桑迪一定要退出
为了这一次的所有停留。
hey, Sandy, what you doing?
嘿，桑迪，你在做什么？
>> Oh, hey, SpongeBob.
>> 哦，嘿，海绵宝宝。
Just putting the finishing
touches on my new invention.
刚刚整理完毕
涉及到我的新发明。
Thanks for assisting me.
You're such a big help.
感谢您对我的帮助。
你真是一个很大的帮助。
No wonder Mr. Krabs relies
on you so heavily.
难怪蟹老板依赖
对你如此沉重。
>>
>>
Hey, Sandy?
嘿，桑迪？
I gotta run to the, uh,
gents room.
我得跑到，呃，
男士房间。
Now if I finish up
with Mr. Krabs,
现在如果我完成了
和蟹老板一起，
that'll free me up
to assist Sandy.
那会让我自由
来协助桑迪。
>> SpongeBob!
>> 海绵宝宝！
I knew I wouldn't
have to fire you.
我知道我不会
必须解雇你。
>> You can rely on me, sir.
>> 您可以信赖我，先生。
I wouldn't want to jeopardize
my employee record.
我不想陷入危险
我的员工记录。
Okay, let's see
what we got here.
好吧，让我们看看
我们在这里得到了什么。
Oh, it says here on page 472,
section C-17,
哦，第 472 页上写着，
C-17 节，
that you need a right-angled
motorized hex drill
你需要一个直角
电动六角钻
to assemble this thing.
组装这个东西。
>> Really?
>> 真的吗？
Why don't you head into town
你为什么不进城去
and pick up one of those
hex drill dealies?
并拿起其中之一
六角钻有优惠吗？
>> I--
>> 我--
>> Or you can sit there
>> 或者你也可以坐在那里
and watch me fill out
your employee report card.
看我填写
您的员工报告卡。
"Dear valued Tom's Toolery
customers,
“亲爱的汤姆的工具
客户，
"we are closed this week
in observance of Porpoise Day.
“我们这周不营业
庆祝海豚日。
Please call again."
请再打电话。”
Barnacles! Where can I find
a motorized hex drill now?
藤壶！我在哪里可以找到
现在有电动六角钻吗？
>> Just finishin' up here.
>> Sandy!
>> 刚刚完成这里。
>> 桑迪！
Uh, oh, hey, Patrick.
What are you doing in town?
呃，哦，嘿，帕特里克。
你在城里做什么？
>> I was just buying
some birthday hats
>> 我刚买
一些生日帽
for my birthday party.
为我的生日聚会。
You didn't forget
my party, did you?
你没有忘记
我的党，你呢？
>> Forget--
>> 忘记--
How could I forget my best
buddy's birthday party, huh?
我怎么能忘记最好的自己
朋友的生日聚会，嗯？
>> Well, you already forgot
one thing.
>> 好吧，你已经忘记了
一件事。
>>
No, I haven't.
>>
不，我没有。
Have I?
我有吗？
>> Hello?
My birthday cake!
>> 你好？
我的生日蛋糕！
>> Oh, yeah, that!
>> 哦，是的，那个！
I was, um, just getting to that.
我，嗯，刚刚开始。
That's why I was here
in town, yeah.
这就是我来这里的原因
在城里，是的。
You are hilarious, Star.
You really are.
你真搞笑，星星。
你确实是。
Now you just go home,
现在你只要回家，
and I'm gonna go get your cake,
you silly guy, you.
我要去拿你的蛋糕
你这个傻家伙，你。
Hi, I need a birthday cake.
你好，我需要一个生日蛋糕。
>> This is what I got.
>> 这就是我得到的。
>> "Sorry about the scabies."
>>“关于疥疮，我深表歉意。”
Um, can you change it to say
happy birthday?
嗯，你能把它改成这样吗
生日快乐吗？
>>
Do you want it or not?
>>
你想要还是不想要？
I haven't got all night.
我一整夜都没有。
>> Yeah, neither do I.
>> 是的，我也没有。
Sandy's drill!
桑迪的演习！
>> SpongeBob!
>> Oh! Hi!
>> 海绵宝宝！
>>哦！你好！
I was just--
我只是——
Making sure you have
all your hardware.
确保你有
你所有的硬件。
>> That's an unusual getup.
>> 这是一种不寻常的装束。
>> Oh, I thought I'd be...
>> 哦，我以为我会...
A little festive, you know,
for the scientists.
有点节日气氛，你知道，
对于科学家来说。
>> And the birthday cake?
>> 生日蛋糕呢？
>> Uh--
>> 呃--
>> Greetings,
my distinguished colleagues.
>> 您好，
尊敬的同事们。
Tonight you will witness
an invention so revolutionary
今晚你将见证
如此革命性的发明
it may change modern science
forever.
它可能会改变现代科学
永远。
Now to demonstrate,
现在来演示一下，
my assistant here will disrobe
and enter the machine.
我这里的助理会脱衣服
并进入机器。
>> What?
>> 什么？
>> Some of you may be wondering
>> 你们中有些人可能想知道
why the test subject
is disrobing.
为什么测试对象
正在脱衣服。
It's because--
这是因为——
what's under your gown?
你的礼服下面是什么？
>> Oh, must be that spicy kelp
I ate earlier.
>>哦，一定是那个辣海带
我之前吃过。
I've got to use the laboratory.
我必须使用实验室。
I'll be right Pat--Back.
我马上就回来。
Back--I'll be right--
回来--我会的--
>> You finally made it!
>> 你终于成功了！
>> Yeah, big traffic storm.
>> 是的，大交通风暴。
>> Well, just leave my present
over on the present table.
>> 好吧，留下我的礼物吧
在目前的桌子上。
>> Your present?
>> 你的礼物？
>> I'm so excited I've been
waiting for a whole year!
>> 我太兴奋了
等了整整一年！
>> Oh, I've got it!
It's right there.
>>哦，我明白了！
它就在那里。
Ta dah!
哒哒！
All wrapped and ready to go.
一切都包装好，准备出发。
>> Well, what are you
waiting for, buddy?
>> 那么，你是什么？
还在等吗，伙计？
Serve up the cake
so I can tear into that present.
把蛋糕端上来
这样我就可以撕碎这份礼物了。
>> The cake!
I must've left it at Sandy's.
>> 蛋糕！
我一定是把它忘在桑迪家了。
>> You took it to Sandy's?
>> No!
>> 你把它带到桑迪家了？
>> 不！
I said, uh,
"the bakery delivers,
我说，呃，
“面包店提供，
isn't that handy?"
这不是很方便吗？”
In fact, I think
I hear them outside.
其实我觉得
我听到他们在外面。
Wait right there
while I go check.
就在那里等一下
当我去检查时。
>> SpongeBob.
>> 海绵宝宝。
>> Barnacles.
>> 藤壶。
>> I apologize for the delay.
>> 对于延迟，我深表歉意。
Now let's continue
the demonstration.
现在我们继续
示威。
I give you...
我给你...
This device gives
a single laborer
该设备提供
一个工人
the productivity of five,
six, seven,
五人的生产力，
六、七、
up to eight workers,
which is great for management.
最多八名工人，
这对于管理来说非常有用。
But it's also a boon
for the worker
但这也是一种福利
对于工人
because they'll always get
high marks
因为他们总会得到
高分
on their employee report cards
在他们的员工报告卡上
>> I was just looking
at your employee report card.
>> 我只是想看看
在您的员工报告卡上。
>> Ah, the telescope!
>> 啊，望远镜！
>> Without further delay,
I shall initiate Proto-Sequence.
>> 事不宜迟，
我将启动原始序列。
>> Uh, Sandy, I hate to delay
the proceedings,
>> 呃，桑迪，我讨厌拖延
诉讼程序，
but, um, I forgot to mail in
但是，嗯，我忘了邮寄
this mail-in rebate, and...
这个邮寄回扣，以及...
I'll be right back.
我马上回来。
Okay, let's get started,
Mr. Krabs.
好吧，让我们开始吧，
蟹老板。
>> What happened
to your clothes, boy?
>> 发生了什么
你的衣服，男孩？
>> Uh, sardines.
>> 呃，沙丁鱼。
Yeah, I was attacked
by a can of wild sardines.
是的，我被攻击了
一罐野生沙丁鱼。
Now let's finish this telescope.
现在让我们完成这个望远镜。
>> Boy?
>> 男孩？
Hold on, boy.
坚持住，男孩。
You're supposed to be using
that motorized hex drill.
你应该使用
那个电动六角钻。
Where is it?
它在哪里？
>>
I left it at Patrick's rock.
>>
我把它留在了帕特里克的岩石上。
>> Patrick's rock?
>> 帕特里克的摇滚？
What's it doin' there?
它在那里做什么？
SpongeBob, wait!
海绵宝宝，等等！
Get back here, boy!
回到这里吧，孩子！
>>
>>
>> SpongeBob,
why are your clothes invisible?
>> 海绵宝宝,
为什么你的衣服是看不见的？
>> Never mind that.
>> 没关系。
Can I please borrow
your present?
我可以借一下吗
你的礼物？
>> No, no! No, you can't borrow
my birthday present.
>> 不，不！不，你不能借
我的生日礼物。
>> Not even for a minute?
>> 一分钟都没有吗？
>> No, not until they deliver
my birthday cake.
>> 不，直到他们交付为止
我的生日蛋糕。
>>
Okay, I'll be right back.
>>
好的，我马上回来。
>> Hold on!
Where you going?
>> 坚持住！
你要去哪里？
>> I'm here.
>> 我在这儿。
>> Hold it!
>> 坚持住！
Where's my little assistant
going this time?
我的小助理在哪里
这次去吗？
>> Your little assistant?
>> 你的小助手？
That's my assistant
you're talking to.
这是我的助理
你正在说话。
What's going on around here?
这附近发生了什么事？
>> Yeah, I'd like to know also.
>> 嗯，我也想知道。
What kinda birthday present
is this?
什么样的生日礼物
这是吗？
>> Hey, SpongeBob was supposed
to bring that to me!
>> 嘿，海绵宝宝应该是
把它带给我！
>> That looks like
my  power drill.
>> 看起来像
我的电钻。
You've got a lot of explainin'
to do, mister.
你有很多解释
要做，先生。
I've got something to say.
I've got something--
我有话要说。
我有东西——
I have got something to say!
我有话要说！
>>
>>
I know you all had important
things going on tonight:
我知道你们都有重要的经历
今晚发生的事情：
Mr. Krabs with your telescope;
蟹老板带着你的望远镜；
Patrick, your birthday;
帕特里克，你的生日；
and Sandy, you had
this big presentation.
还有桑迪，你有
这场盛大的演讲。
I just couldn't say no
to any of you.
我只是无法拒绝
给你们任何一个人。
>> Aw, you overextended
yourself.
>> 噢，你太过分了
你自己。
>> Yeah, you should have said
something.
>> 是的，你应该说
某事。
>> We could've
worked something out.
>> 我们本来可以
解决了一些问题。
>> Aw, you know,
you guys are right.
>> 哦，你知道，
你们是对的。
It was silly to think I could be
in three places at once.
认为我可以是很愚蠢的
同时在三个地方。
>> Nonsense, SpongeBob.
Of course you can,
>> 废话，海绵宝宝。
当然可以，
if you'll just step
into the Proto-Generator 2000.
如果你愿意迈出一步
进入 Proto-Generator 2000。
First, I close
the Proto-Chamber.
首先，我关闭
原型室。
And finally...
最后...
>> Oh!
>>哦！
>> As you can see,
>> 如您所见，
I've produced two clones
of my subject
我已经产生了两个克隆体
我的主题
which will allow him to honor
all the commitments
这将使他能够尊重
所有的承诺
he's made this evening.
他今天晚上就成功了。
Did you hear that, SpongeBob?
你听到了吗，海绵宝宝？
You can be in three places
at once now.
你可以在三个地方
现在立刻。
>>
>>
captioning by captionmax
www.captionmax.com
字幕由captionmax提供
♪ ♪